

CONTACT

54 11 5930 1321

javiergiordano@gmail.com

www.javiergiordano.com.ar

in https://www.linkedin.com/i
n/javier-giordano/

EDUCATION

2020 ITCOLLEGE

• AWS - Architecting

2019 ACAMICA

• Data Science

2019 BOOTCAMPS

- Python for computer vision
 OpenCV and Deep Learning
- Python for data science and Machine Learning

2018 FUNDACIÓN TELEFÓNICA

 Machine Learning and Business Intelligence

SKILLS

- English B1/B2
- Business intelligence
- Data Science
- Python
- Power BI
- Computer Visión
- SQL
- JavaScript

JAVIER GIORDANO

DATA SCIENTIST

PROFILE

I am a Data Scientist with a strong business vision. I am currently deepening my skills in Generative AI and its adoption in digital transformation processes. I am proactive, curious, and enjoy transforming business needs into technical requirements. I thoroughly enjoy researching and learning new tools to find creative solutions to everyday challenges

EXPERIENCE

Soko Solutions

2024 - Actualidad

GenIA - Python Dev

- Developed tools in Python for NLP tasks.
- Generated reports using large language models (LLMs).
- · Prompt engineering.

GCBA - SSPPBE

2022 - 2024

Team leader -

- Team leader in the Data Analysis and Visualization team.
- Identified data management needs and developed data governance and exploitation strategies.
- Created and automated dashboards in Power BI.
- Wrote queries and generated tables using SQL in AWS Athena.

HSBC 2020 - 2021

Data Visualization consultor

- Designed and developed an interactive dashboard for internal team management in the transformation department.
- Made with D3.js DC.js Crossfilter.js

DameLuna 2020 - 2021

Digital Transformation consultor

- Developed brand manual and corporate identity.
- Created digital ecosystem and marketing plan.
- Designed and developed e-commerce platform.

TECH STACK

- Data Science: SQL, Python, Pytorch, BeautifulSoup, Numpy, Pandas, OpenCV, YOLO.
- Data Visualization: D3.js, Crossfilter.js, DC.js, Leaflet.js, Dash, Power BI, Tableau.
- Web: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Three.js, WebGL, React, Bootstrap.